Rishi Vishnoi

Senior Test Engineer at Xoriant Solutions

Summary

8+ years of IT experience working in different domains i.e. BigData, Automation and Software Testing. Expertise in performing data analytics on large data sets using different tools and techniques. Worked on Enterprise level Storage, Security, Reporting products i.e. Hitachi Data Instance Director, McAfee Endpoint Protection, Symantec NetBackup, Symantec OpsCenter.

Skills:

- Hadoop Ecosystem: HDFS, MapReduce, YARN, Flume, Sqoop, Oozie, Hive, Pig, HBase, Ambari, Tez, Zookeper, Apache Spark, Elastic Search, Kibana, Spark Streaming, Apache Zeppline, MIT Kerberos
- Sood understanding of Apache Spark Framework, Hadoop Distributed File System.
- Worked on Cloudera Distribution Hadoop (CDH5.4), Hortonworks Data Platform(HDP2.5) distributions and configured the cluster for the same using Ambari and managed the same.
- Sood understanding and working exposure of performing analytics on data stored in RDBMS or NoSQL databases using SQL queries.
- Automation: REST API, Newman, Postman, Selenium WebDriver, TestNG
- -> Programming Language : Scala, Python and Core Java
- -> Code checkin and task updation tool: SVN, GIT, Confluence, Stash and Jenkins.
- Manual Testing: Functional, Regression, Integration,

Web Testing, Localization, 508 Compliance, Interoperability and Security Testing.

- Tools: Mercury Quality Center, JIRA, Bugzilla, Test Complete, Workbench, JAWS
- -> Good in Test Planning, Test Execution, Defect Reporting and document creation.
- -> Expertise in working on different Unix and Windows platforms i.e. Linux, Suse, AIX and Windows
- Sood in troubleshooting system related issues related to network,packages,Operating System installation,upgrading kernel or TL levels in AIX.

Certifications:

- -> HDP Certified Spark Developer ,Feb 2018
- -> IBM Tivoli 5.5 Administration ,IBM Tivoli 5.4 Implementation Certified
- ->> Oracle 9i Basic Certified.

Strongly self-motivated, Team Player and eager to learn new things and getting productive in short span of time.

Experience

Senior Test Engineer at Xoriant

August 2015 - Present

Working as Automation Engineer for client Hitachi on multiple Automation and Analytics assignments

- a) Web Automation of Reporting Tool using Selenium + Python including coverage on multiple browsers .
- b) Worked on inhouse test framework component creation and developing regression suite from scratch for multiple storage components i.e. Filesystem, Oracle, VmWare using REST API+ Python +Postman combination to automate manual tests.
- c) Worked on developing backend scripts for data validation, creating connection to Oracle database on multiple operating systems, generating data inside database, database service stop/start etc.
- d) Involved in performing POC's by defining cluster environments, Creation of cluster using CDH 5.4 or HDP 2.5 distribution ,Performing analytics on variety of data sets fetched from multiple data sources using different tools i.e. YARN, Sqoop, Hive, Pig, Flume, Oozie, Tez etc. Additionally performed Sentiment Analysis on survey based data for projection to wider audience.

SQA Engineer at Symantec

March 2013 - August 2015 (2 years 6 months)

Worked on enterprise level Web Based Reporting product i.e. OpsCenter and storage product NetBackup .

- a) Majorly involved in testing core areas of NetBackup and Opscenter i.e.Reporting, SLP,Catalogue,Cloud storage, Java GUI parity with Windows GUI and filing bugs around the same.
- b) Owner for qualifying Java GUI of NetBackup and Opscenter against 508 Compliance standards and creating document to be published across different countries to meet release standards.
- c) Key member in automation team for developing automation suite for install upgrade automation for Opscenter and doing web automation using Selenium+ Java.
- d) Expertise in working on JAWS tool for compliance testing.
- e) Expertise in performing i18n testing i.e. Localization and Internationalization testing for Enterprise products and creating test scenarios accordingly.

Handled multiple tasks in team i.e. manual testing, automation task along with hardware management and maintaining automation suite for OpsCenter by fixing existing and new issues in the scripts .

Senior SQA Engineer at McAfee

June 2011 - February 2013 (1 year 9 months)

Worked majorly on Embedded Systems and different Unix flavours to test the functionality of the security product "Solidcore" through manual and automation testing.

- 1 Designed Test Cases for checking the basic functionality of the product for different features like Application Control, Change Control and importing to QC.
- 2. Performed different types of testing Regression testing, Stress Testing, Soak Testing, Performance Testing i.e. Postmark and End to End testing for the software released on multiple Unix based Operating Systems and on embedded devices and reporting bugs found in Bugzilla.
- 3 .Created script for AIX servers that can switch between different LPAR disk and does the product related testing along with product installation,uninstallation,logs generation, copying logs to the result server and sending mail to the end user
- 4. Good knowledge of NIM servers, LPARS in AIX and creating new AIX images on LPAR servers
- 5. Worked as a active member of customer escalation team and creating customer setups to get their issue reproduced locally.

Associate SQA Engineer at Symantec

December 2009 - June 2011 (1 year 7 months)

Worked majorly on Storage products Symantec NetBackup and Pure Disk focussing mainly on technologies BMR and Deduplication.

- a) Performed end to end Functional Testing for the above technologies on different Windows and Unix flavour operating systems i.e. Rhel,Suse,Aix,Solaris,HPux.
- b) Qualified NetBackup product BMR functionality for IPv6 feature and tested config file parameters that enable Deduplication to work.
- c) Performed different types of testing (Install/Upgrade, Feature Testing, Acceptance, Browser compatibility, Performance and Load) as per test scenarios defined.
- d) Learned storage fundamentals and virtualization concepts to get better understanding of the product.

Education

Integral University

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science, 2005 - 2009

Lucknow Public School

Eng, Phy, Chem. Math, Computer Science, 2002 - 2005

Honors and Awards

Good Work

Rishi Vishnoi

Senior Test Engineer at Xoriant Solutions



Contact Rishi on LinkedIn